wikimatrix.org 2019-04-22

# Privacy | WikiMatrix

This privacy policy describes the treatment of personal data that we collect through all your activities that refer to this privacy policy. This includes visiting and using our websites www.wikimatrix.org, www.forummatrix.org, www.weblogmatrix.org and www.podcatchermatrix.org (hereinafter collectively referred to as "website").

Our website may be used without entering personal information. Different rules may apply to certain services on our site, however, and are explained separately below. We collect your personal information in accordance with the provisions of German data protection statutes. Information is considered personal if it can be associated exclusively to a specific natural person. The legal framework for data protection may be found in the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) as well as the German Federal Data Protection Act (BDSG) and the Telemedia Act (TMG). The provisions below serve to provide information as to the manner, extent and purpose for collecting, using and processing personal information by the provider.

Responsible in the sense of the data protection basic regulation and other national data protection laws of the member states as well as other data protection-juridical regulations is

CosmoCode GmbH  
Prenzlauer Allee 36G  
10405 Berlin  
Phone: +49 30 814 50 40 70  
E-Mail: [wikimatrix@cosmocode.de](mailto:wikimatrix@cosmocode.de)

If you have any questions about this privacy statement, please contact our data protection officer as follows:

Data Protection Officer  
CosmoCode GmbH  
Prenzlauer Allee 36G  
10405 Berlin  
E-Mail: [datenschutz@cosmocode.de](mailto:datenschutz@cosmocode.de)

Please be aware that data transfer via the internet is subject to security risks and, therefore, complete protection against third-party access to transferred data cannot be ensured.

## Cookies

Our website makes use of cookies. Cookies are small text files stored on the user's computer and transmitted to our site by the user. Therefore, you as a user have full control over the use of cookies. You can deactivate or restrict the transmission of cookies by changing the settings in your Internet browser. Cookies that have already been saved can be deleted at any time. This can also be done automatically. You should be aware, however, that by doing so you may not be able to make full use of all the functions of our website.

## Server Data

For technical reasons, data such as the following, which your internet browser transmits to us or to our web space provider (so called server log files), is collected: - type and version of the browser you use - operating system - websites that linked you to our site (referrer URL) - pages that you visit - date and time of your visit - your Internet Protocol (IP) address. This anonymous data is stored separately from any personal information you may have provided, thereby making it impossible to connect it to any particular person.

The data is used for statistical purposes in order to improve our website and services and to protect our services against malicious activity. The collection of data for the provision of the website and the storage of data in log files is mandatory for the operation of the website. Consequently, there is no possibility for the user to object.

Log files are automatically deleted after 30 days unless needed as evidence during an abuse investigation.

## SSL encoding

To protect the security of your data during transmission, we use state-of-the-art encryption methods (e.g. SSL) via HTTPS.

## Contacting Us

On our website we offer you the opportunity to contact us by email. In such an event, information provided by the user is stored for the purpose of facilitating communications with the user. 

All e-mails directed at us are processed by our e-mail provider Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043 USA, under an existing data processing agreement.

Please note that unencrypted emails may be intercepted and read by third parties during the transfer. If you wish to communicate encrypted, you may contact us to provide you with an end-to-end encryption key.

The user has the right to revoke his consent to the processing of his personal data at any time. If the user contacts us by e-mail, he can object to the storage of his personal data at any time. In such a case, the conversation cannot be continued and all personal data stored in the course of establishing contact will be deleted.

## Registration on our website

Registration on our website is completely optional and only needed if you want to provide content (like maintaining product data or advertising services). We collect your email address and tax information such as your country of residence and tax identifiaction number if needed.

When registering at our website you agree that we will contact you by email to inform you about changes regarding the data you maintain at our website. As part of the registration process, your consent to the processing of this data is obtained.

The data will be deleted as soon as they are no longer necessary to achieve the purpose for which they were collected. This applies to the data collected during the registration process if the registration on our website is cancelled or modified.

If the data are necessary for the fulfillment of a contract or for the implementation of pre-contractual measures, they will be stored for as long as they are necessary for the implementation of the contract. Even after the conclusion of the contract, it may be necessary to store personal data of the contractual partner in order to comply with contractual or legal obligations.

As a user you have the possibility to cancel the registration at any time. You can change the data stored about you at any time. However, if the data are necessary for the fulfilment of a contract or for the implementation of pre-contractual measures, premature deletion of the data is only possible insofar as there are no contractual or legal obligations to the contrary.

We will also provide you with information about the personal data we have stored about you at any time. We will be happy to correct or delete them at your request, provided that there are no legal storage obligations to the contrary. To contact us in this context, please use the contact details given at the end of this data protection declaration.

## Error Reporting

The software providing our website should ideally be bug-free. However unforseen errors may happen. These errors are automatically logged and collected in our incident management system. Collected errors contain context data that helps us to reproduce and fix the error. This context data may contain some of your personal information such as IP address, email address and browser identification. This data is only collected in the rare case of unforeseen errors and will be deleted after the underlying problem has been fixed. The data is not forwarded to third parties.

## Use of Google Analytics with anonymization

Our website uses Google Analytics, a web analysis service from Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043 USA, hereinafter referred to as “Google“. Google Analytics employs so-called “cookies“, text files that are stored to your computer in order to facilitate an analysis of your use of the site.

The information generated by these cookies, such as time, place and frequency of your visits to our site, including your IP address, is transmitted to Google’s location in the US and stored there.

We use Google Analytics with an IP anonymization feature on our website. In doing so, Google abbreviates and thereby anonymizes your IP address before transferring it from member states of the European Union or signatory states to the Agreement on the European Economic Area.

Google will use this information to evaluate your usage of our site, to compile reports on website activity for us, and to provide other services related to website- and internet usage. Google may also transfer this information to third parties if this is required by law or to the extent this data is processed by third parties on Google´s behalf.

Google states that it will in never associate your IP address with other data held by Google. You can prevent cookies from being installed by adjusting the settings on your browser software accordingly. You should be aware, however, that by doing so you may not be able to make full use of all the functions of our website.

Google also offers a disabling option for the most common browsers, thus providing you with greater control over the data which is collected and processed by Google. If you enable this option, no information regarding your website visit is transmitted to Google Analytics. However, the activation does not prevent the transmission of information to us or to any other web analytics services we may use. For more information about the disabling option provided by Google, and how to enable this option, visit <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en>

## Privacy Statement for using Google Adsense

This site may use Google AdSense, a service for including advertisements from Google Inc. ("Google"). Google AdSense uses "cookies", text files that are stored on your computer and allows the analysis of the use of the site. Google AdSense uses also use web beacons (invisible images). Through this web beacons, information can be evaluated as the visitor traffic on these pages.

The information generated by cookies and web beacons on this website (including your IP address) and delivery of advertising formats to a Google server in the U.S. and stored there. This information can be passed on from Google to contractors of Google. Google is your IP address but not combined with other data you have stored.

You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser, but we point out that you can use in this case not all features of this website. By using this site you agree to the processing of data about you by Google in the manner described above and for the purpose.

You can configure ad personalization through Google's [Ad Settings Tool](https://adssettings.google.com/).

Please also see [Google's Privacy & Terms page](https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites)

## Information/Cancellation/Deletion

If personal data is processed by you, you are the data subject within the meaning of GDPR and you are entitled to the following rights:

  * Right of access
  * Right to rectification
  * Right to limitation of processing
  * Right to erasure

On the basis of the Federal Data Protection Act, you may contact us at no cost if you have questions relating to the collection, processing or use of your personal information, if you wish to request the correction, blocking or deletion of the same, or if you wish to cancel explicitly granted consent. Please note that you have the right to have incorrect data corrected or to have personal data deleted, where such claim is not barred by any legal obligation to retain this data.

You have the right to complain to a supervisory authority, in particular in the Member State of your residence, place of work or place of presumed infringement, if you consider that the processing of your personal data is in breach of the GDPR.

The supervisory authority to which the complaint was submitted will inform the complainant of the status and outcome of the complaint, including the possibility of a judicial remedy under Article 78 GDPR.
